Hey everyone, and thanks for checking
back into the cryptoverse.
Today, we're going to talk about
Bitcoin, the winds of winter. If you
guys like the content, make sure you
subscribe to the channel, give the video
a thumbs up, and also check out the sale
on intothecryptoverse premium at
intothecryptoverse.com.
Link is in the description below. You'll
get access to a lot of charts that we
use to navigate these crypto market
cycles, as well as charts for stocks, uh
commodities, and and macros. So, make
sure to check that out. Link's in the
description below.
As a reminder, ticket prices for the
first ITC conference will be going up on
September 1st, so make sure you guys get
your ticket if you would like to attend.
Now, we did these videos 4 years ago,
where we said Bitcoin, the winds of
winter. It was kind of like throughout
2022, we made these videos. Well, here
we are. We find ourselves in 2026. Um
you know, Bitcoin's trading around 62 to
63,000,
and it just feels kind of dead.
Right? Social interest is trending down.
If you look at our social risk metric,
that you can follow along on the website
with,
that's been trending down.
Bitcoin is getting squeezed essentially
between the 200-week moving average and
the bear market resistance band.
My guess is that it it eventually breaks
down kind of in line with how prior
cycles played out, which would sort of
necessitate, perhaps, like a an eventual
correction in stocks. So, I don't really
think that correction in stocks is going
to happen until September, and probably
not even until mid to late September.
But normally, Bitcoin shows weakness
before stocks do.
So,
the reason why it it it's so hard right
now is because you have Bitcoin just
going absolutely nowhere and the stock
market printing new highs. But again,
this is why index funds are, in my
opinion, not financial advice, have
always been a great part of my portfolio
because they do generally trend higher.
Not always, right? Sometimes they'll go
down, but it it allows you to breathe a
little bit, especially when Bitcoin's
going through these bear markets. Now,
the reason why it's so hard is because
after the June low, you guys probably
remember me talking about this, um you
know, leading into the summer, is that
you'll likely form a low in the summer,
in June or July, that then acts as the
low for a while. And then after the low
forms, volatility compresses.
Right? Volatility compresses after the
summer low, as you can see in the last
several market cycles.
And on our website, you we actually have
a volatility chart, right? So, if you
look at volatility for Bitcoin,
um over the last, say, 60 days, it's
relatively low right now. Like it's
really low, and usually when it starts
to get low like this, volatility will
then often pick back up, whether it's to
the upside or the downside. Okay? So, I
can't promise you that the next move is
to the downside, but I do think that
there is a
I do think there's a likelihood that
that is the way it breaks, and then it
scares a lot of people, it ushers in the
market cycle bottom. And then from
there, ideally, Bitcoin then begins a
new bull market.
But you'll see that volatility is
getting incredibly low.
60-day volatility is at 1.47%
and it just kind of hover the line at
that level. We don't tend to go much
lower than that. So, volatility is
likely about to pick back up a lot.
If you look at it on a 30-day time
frame, it's at 1.16%,
right? Like it's getting pretty low, and
there's not that many times in history
where the volatility of Bitcoin was
getting to be this low. You could also
look at it over say 180 days and see
that recently volatility has just fallen
off a cliff.
So, the winds of winter continue to
blow. And
it feels cold,
even though it's summer, right? But in
the cryptoverse, it's winter. Social
risk is trending down.
Social metrics across the cryptoverse,
like views to crypto YouTube channels,
in general, again, trending down.
But we've seen this before. The last
time the social risk was .2 in August of
a midterm year was not 2022, it was in
fact in 2018.
And we're still tracking
the 2018 market structure almost
perfectly.
As you can see,
the low in February, the lower low in
the summer, it's it's all the same, the
lower high in May.
It's very very similar.
And so,
the winds of winter press on.
Bitcoin volatility is is compressing,
and as we get out of the summer
and go into the fall, volatility is
likely going to pick up a lot.
A lot.
So, do not be lulled into a false sense
of complacency here. All right?
Because this is how it always feels.
Kind of in back half of the summer
of midterm years.
And then something happens.
Who knows what? Doesn't matter.
Something happens.
And and the market
wakes back up.
And people will then blame that event.
Right? They'll be like, well, it was
because of this.
But
I don't we don't need a narrative,
right?
Whether it's yields going up because the
Fed refuses to raise rates, whether it's
just the stock market getting a
correction later this year, whether it's
some, you know, some disagreements
within Bitcoin itself, which there have
been some. Um or
whether it has to do with
AI and and some of that the hacks that
we've seen in the cryptoverse,
vulnerabilities that people didn't fully
realize were there. Maybe that
continues. I don't know what the
narrative is.
But you can be rest assured that there
will be one.
So, Bitcoin again right now trading
around 62 to 63,000 dollars. As we've
said previously, the 20-week or the bear
market resistance band and the 200-week
moving average are coming together. And
as they get closer, it's going to force
a decision. It's going to force Bitcoin
to decide which way it's going to break
out. And in order for the on-chain
indicators to fully reset
a break to the downside would allow
that.
Right? It would allow it. And you can
see that on-chain on-chain risk has been
slowly going down.
If you get one more draw down,
that might be it. Right? I mean, like
that would probably reset all the
on-chain indicators.
Like if we get one more drop like we did
back in in May to June
or from, you know, January going into
February, or or October going into to
December, you get one more of those,
you're likely going to see
a lot of these on-chain indicators
completely reset at that point. And then
the justification
for lower prices would be a lot more it
would be a lot more difficult
to justify.
And of course, you could try and justify
lower prices beyond that point based on
the macro or based on the prevailing
narratives, but the four-year cycle
headwind
within just a couple of months or so
will likely become a
tailwind.
But,
we're not quite there yet, right? Like
we're in month 10
of likely a 12-month bear market. Now,
sometimes the bear market goes on for 13
or 14 months, sometimes they're maybe a
little bit less, like 9 months, like
2019.
But,
that's how
this plays out, more than likely. More
than likely that's how I think it plays
out. And if if those if those narratives
don't work, then maybe it's the Fed just
finally deciding to raise rates.
And and it spooks people, people blame
that for Bitcoin breaking below 60K, but
remember in both 2019
and 2018, we were holding 6K for a
while.
Once we broke it, it immediately led to
the market cycle bottom, immediately,
within the next few weeks. Market cycle
bottom was in.
And what's interesting
is
when you look at the
Bitcoin ROI from the bottom,
we're now
on day, let's actually extend this out.
We're now on day 1362.
And the last two only lasted,
you know, 60 70 more days 60 to 80 days
from now.
They didn't last that much longer.
So, I know it feels bleak and and it
feels like things are crumbling and and
if and with the hardware wallet wa- with
the hardware wallet uh hacks,
it it it feels
really bad, right? It it it does. And
I'm not going to I mean it it it it's
kind of led to an identity problem to
some degree. But remember, the hardware
wallet hack
um
is not
a Bitcoin failure.
That's a third-party failure.
The problem is good luck convincing
people of that that don't really care,
right? Good luck. And that's the the
problem that we have is that it's hard
to go out and be like, "Well, yeah, like
that sucks and it and it sucks that that
this company did that, but people are
just going to assume it's all the same
thing, right? They're not going to
differentiate necessarily between
Bitcoin and the ways that people choose
to hold their Bitcoin. They're just
going to say, "You know what? I'd rather
just go buy an AI stock or something."
So, again,
the winds of winter blow on,
but they always blow on
during this part of the midterm year.
Complacency is here.
Volatility
is not here.
But within the next few weeks,
volatility is likely going to pick up a
lot.
And when that happens,
when that happens, if and when that
happens,
be prepared
because
when that phase occurs, the market cycle
bottom
follows almost immediately. It's one of
those things where if you blink,
you miss it.
And that's one of the reasons why like
DCA-ing often is just better because
like in 2022, I bought Bitcoin starting
in in the summer. Kind of like this
time. Like I started in the summer once
we went below 60k.
Um I did the same thing in in 2022.
Um
and then eventually we went lower, but
the problem is that, you know, imagine
if you bought Bitcoin. Imagine if you
didn't buy Bitcoin in the summer of 2022
and then FTX happened.
Maybe you would have been too scared to
buy. And then by by
2023, it didn't really matter if you
bought in the summer or if you bought at
the end of the year. Right? I mean
a few percent, what's a few percent
among friends?
Yeah, in 2018 the drop was a bit more
dramatic, right? I mean it was a 50%
drop.
But I mean, you know, a year and a half
later
it didn't really matter, right? It
didn't really matter a whole lot.
And when that drop occurred
it was scary, right? I mean
we have the benefit now of like looking
at what the chart did, but if you're
only looking at the chart like this,
like imagine you're looking at it on a
like a regular scale and you're looking
at Bitcoin and that's what it's doing.
It's not like you knew for a fact that
it was going to recover at at 3100. It's
not like we knew for a fact it would. We
hoped it would, but we also would have
hoped it would at six or at 6,000 as
well and it didn't. So
one day at a time
we're getting we're getting through the
bear market. The winds of winter
continue to blow
but they're not going to blow forever.
And and once it's over, hopefully we can
go to the next bull market and hopefully
in the next bull market the the industry
can focus on what matters more. And and
that will not just be figuring out
avenues for more money to come into the
space, but to figure out how do we make
the space fundamentally better. How do
we rebuke the meme coin garbage that the
space became associated with? How do we
rebuke that stuff? Let's rebuke the
people that promote it, too.
As we grow, as the industry can do that,
then the industry should have no problem
keeping up with other with other
industries. But, we've had a crisis
problem.
Liquidity
has been tight.
And Bitcoin and crypto are further up
the risk curve than most other things in
the market, and that's why they're able
to go down. And you know, if you're if
you're frustrated that the S&P is going
to new highs while Bitcoin is is still
stuck in traffic on Struggle Street, I
will remind you the same thing happened
in 2014 and in 2018. Right? In 2014 and
2018, Bitcoin was going down. The S&P
was actually still putting in new
all-time highs in 2018 even by
September.
In 2014,
Bitcoin was going down.
S&P turned it up.
It might feel different because 2022,
the S&P went down while Bitcoin went
down.
But,
two of the three times Bitcoin went down
while the S&P went up.
And now, three out of the four times
that has been the case. So, you don't
have to have a stock market bear market
for Bitcoin to be in a bear market.
Bitcoin is in a bear market because it's
following its own cycle, right? The
human psychology that associates with
with this asset dictates that the top
occurs approximately every 4 years, and
then the bottom occurs often times near
the end of the midterm year. We're
getting near the end of the midterm
year. Like, it's already we're already
halfway through August.
You know, we're going to blink and it's
going to be October. And then and you
know, it'll be December before you know,
before we know it, and then it'll be
time to really start talking about, all
right, how do we how do we break back
through, right? How do we break back
through the the bear market resistance
band because normally it it happen any
durable fashion until the pre-halving
year. We didn't get durably through the
bear market resistance band
three cycles ago until
2015.
And then two cycles ago, we didn't get
durably through it. I mean, we still
fell below it eventually, but we didn't
get really back back through it and held
it for many many months
until April of 2019.
And then last cycle, we got through it
in
January.
I think we'll get through it.
We just need a few more months. And then
once a few more months pass,
I think we should have no problem
getting back through the bear market
resistance band and ideally turning it
into the bull market support band. If
you guys like the content, make sure you
subscribe to the channel, give the video
a thumbs up. Again, check out the
conference coming up in Miami, November
20th through the 22nd. Ticket prices are
going up in just over 2 weeks, so make
sure you guys get your ticket now before
that occurs. I will see you guys next
time. Bye.